And now over to my Mac people.
이제 맥을 담당하는 분들에게 넘길게요
And I have news for you.
알려드릴 게 있어요
It's exactly the same thing.
완전히 똑같아요
You go to a favorite browser, you go to Alarm.com, you'll see the same screen.
즐겨찾기 브라우저로 가거나 알람으로 가요 같은 화면이 보일 거예요
You press download and then download for Mac OS.
다운로드를 누르고 Mac OS를 다운로드해요
It will of course download it locally.
물론 로컬로 다운로드 되죠
You will then run the installer and it will install it.
그런 다음 설치 관리자를 실행하면 설치되죠
You then bring up a terminal window and you bring up a terminal window by going to applications and
그런 다음 터미널 윈도우를 불러옵니다 어플리케이션과 유틸리티로 가서 터미널
utilities and then terminal.
윈도우를 불러오죠
And when you bring up that terminal window as it comes up here, you type the same instruction Olama
터미널 창을 불러와서 여기 올라옵니다 동일한 지침을 올라마 런이라고 입력하세요
And now the name of the model, which in our case is llama 3.2, the very latest small model from meta.
모델의 이름은, 우리 경우엔 llama 3이죠 2번, 메타에서 나온 최신 소형 모델이에요
And it will then come up.
그럼 떠오를 거예요
It will probably take a minute or two because it will need to download the 2 billion parameters associated
1, 2분 정도 걸릴 겁니다 3과 관련된 20억 개의 매개 변수를
with with 3.2, but then it will be running just like this.
다운로드 해야 하니까요 2개요, 하지만 그러면 이렇게 작동할 거예요
And now again we can try and put it to good use.
이제 다시 좋은 일에 쓸 수 있게 됐어요 Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it
We can ask it this time will use a different language.
이번엔 다른 언어로 물어볼 거예요
Why not?
왜요?
Let's say I am trying to learn French.
제가 프랑스어를 배우려고 한다고 가정해 보죠
I am a complete beginner.
전 완전히 초보예요
Please have a conversation with me to teach me French.
프랑스어 좀 가르쳐 주세요
And let's see how it does.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
The first thing you'll notice is that it's a lot faster.
가장 먼저 눈에 띄는 건 훨씬 빠르다는 거예요
And that's because I'm actually running on a mac with an M1 chip.
M1 칩이 달린 맥으로 작동하기 때문이죠
And what we were seeing earlier was an emulation of a PC.
아까 본 건 PC의 에뮬레이션이었어요
So of course this is a bit faster.
비트가 좀 더 빠르죠
Your computer may be somewhere in between those two, depending on your architecture.
여러분의 컴퓨터는 그 둘 사이 어딘가에 있을 겁니다 여러분의 아키텍처에 따라서요
So off it's gone with the start and you can see that it's done a fab job.
시작과 함께 꺼냈는데 아주 잘 된 걸 볼 수 있죠
It's clearly given a bunch of different options.
다양한 선택지가 주어졌어요
It's explained itself.
설명이 됐어요
It's super impressive.
정말 인상적이에요
Uh, let's say uh, sure.
이렇게 해두죠
So I'm not actually answering his question, but there we go.
질문에 대답하는 건 아니지만 어쨌든 됐네요
You get the idea.
Get it, Get it 아시겠죠?
And the point I wanted to make again is that this is, in fact, a paid commercial product on an app
다시 강조하고 싶은 점은 이건 사실 제가 사용하는 앱의 유료 상업 제품이라는
that I'm using.
거예요
And here we have it.
여기 있네요
We have built effectively a commercial project for free, using open source in a matter of minutes,
오픈 소스를 이용해 몇 분 만에 상업 프로젝트를 무료로 진행했습니다 컴퓨터에
just immediately unleashing the power of an LLM on your computer.
LLM의 힘을 즉시 발휘할 수 있죠
So I now have an exercise for you right away.
그래서 바로 실습을 준비했어요
I'd like you to of course, do this.
물론 이렇게 해 주세요
Install it, make sure that it works.
설치하고 작동하는지 확인해요
If you have any problems whatsoever, then you can always contact me at any point.
무슨 문제가 생기면 언제든 연락해요
Feel free to message me or send me an email or LinkedIn with me and ask for help.
언제든 제게 메시지를 보내거나 이메일이나 링크드인을 보내 도움을 청하세요
But hopefully this is a really easy install that will have you up and running.
하지만 설치가 쉬워서 잘 작동하면 좋겠네요
Do this.
이렇게 해요
Have a quick experiment with a with a language.
언어를 가지고 빠르게 실험해 볼게요
Pick a language maybe one you don't know and try it out.
모르는 언어를 골라서 한번 해 보세요
And then the next thing to try is I'd like you to experiment with different models.
다음으로는 다양한 모델을 실험해 보세요
So if we go back to the llama page, you'll see that there's a model heading up here.
llama 페이지로 돌아가면 모델이 위로 향하고 있는 게 보이시죠
And for both PC and Mac people, it's the same thing.
PC와 Mac 모두 같은 거예요
You can see some different models and read about the story behind them.
다양한 모델을 보고 그 뒤에 숨겨진 이야기를 들을 수 있죠
Llama 3.2 from Meta Jama from Google, which is its open source low parameter version.
라마 3요 구글 메타 자마에서 2개요 오픈 소스 매개 변수 버전이 낮죠
Quan, which is a powerhouse of a model from Alibaba Cloud, which is less well known, but it is one
콴은 동력원인 알리바바 클라우드의 모델로 less는 알려졌지만 가장 강력한
of the strongest.
모델 중 하나죠
You can click on a model and you will then see the different versions of it, and over here is the way
모델을 클릭하면 다양한 버전을 볼 수 있어요 여기서 실행할
that you can run it.
수 있죠
You can simply press that button there to copy it to the clipboard, and then paste it into your PowerShell
저 버튼을 눌러 클립보드로 복사한 다음 PowerShell이나 터미널에 붙여넣으면
or your terminal.
돼요
And these are the various different versions of it.
이건 다양한 버전이에요
And you can just go back to models, browse through them.
모델로 돌아가서 살펴볼 수 있어요
Experiment 53.5 from Microsoft.
53번째 실험이에요 마이크로소프트에서 5년요
Also very powerful model and you can read more about them.
아주 강력한 모델이고 더 자세히 읽어볼 수 있어요
Uh, experiment with them.
실험해 보려고요
And I would like to ask you to try this out for a new language.
이걸 새로운 언어로 사용해 보세요
Try exploring, maybe try and learn something completely different and use different models and see
완전히 다른 것을 탐구하고 배우려고 노력하세요 다른 모델을 사용해 보고
if you can figure out which models are best for you.
어떤 모델이 가장 좋은지 알아내세요
As you pick some of the larger models, they may be slower on your computer, so find out which models
대형 모델을 고를수록 컴퓨터에서 느리게 보일 수 있으니 어떤 모델이 가장 잘 작동하는지
perform the best and give you the best results.
알아보고 가장 좋은 결과를 내세요
That's your exercise and then I will see you for the next time when we will.
오늘 한 운동으로 다음에 다시 만나요
Then do things like introductions and course and all that stuff.
소개나 수업 같은 걸 하는 거죠
See you then.
그때 봐요